



Duje Duša

Nationality: Croatian Date of birth: 1 Jul 1994 Gender: Male

Carrier Phone number: (+385) 958887099 Email address: duje.dusa@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/duje-duša-673016227

Website: https://dujedusa.github.io

• Home: Hektorovićeva 24, 21000 Split (Croatia)

ABOUT ME

I'm a JavaScript Developer oriented and dedicated to Web Development, focusing primarily on front-end frameworks with 3 years of experience in Angular and 1 year experience in web components using Stencil.js. I've previously also worked with .NET Core & EF Core back-end frameworks in combination with SQL relational databases.

Eager and looking forward to upgrading my knowledge with Web Technologies, Responsive Design Systems, and Web Accessibility to become a fully competent Web Developer. To enhance my skills, I built a simple portfolio website using React.js and a few personal projects as well as reading articles, documentation, and books about code.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer

Valcon Croatia [1 Feb 2024 - Current]

Address: Ul. Domovinskog rata 61, 21000, Split, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: https://valcon.com/hr

Name of unit or department: Cloud Software Engineering - Business or sector: Professional, scientific and

technical activities

Schiphol

MVP application for projects and project related permits management developed using Angular and NX monorepo.

Tasks performed:

- Utilizing NX monorepo, module and feature based approach
- Creating feature based components and views based on design system
- Following DRY and clean code principles, guided by a senior colleague and mentor
- · Working in a tight schedule time frame
- Implementing solutions missing from design system to match look and feel of the rest of application
- Actively conducting code reviews

Frontend Developer

Valcon Croatia [1 Jan 2023 - Current]

Address: Ul. Domovinskog rata 61, 21000, Split, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: https://valcon.com/hr

Name of unit or department: Cloud Software Engineering - Business or sector: Professional, scientific and

technical activities

Valcon Nebula Platform

Internal application for developing UI library based on web components. Library is utilizing Stencil.js, framwork agnostic build tool, to create reusable, scalable, small and fast web components that can run anywhere.



Documentation is based on Storybook, frontend workshop for building UI components and pages in isolation where usage and testing can be leveraged.

· Tasks performed:

- Pioneered in researching, creating and developing web components
- Creating small, reusable and scalable, well documented web components
- Implemented custom CSS architecture using ITCSS approach
- Developed and tested pixel-perfect components based on design system
- Starting to include Web Accesibility practices
- Creating documentation through Storybook
- Implementing Storybook stories that shows and describes web component abilities
- Writing documentation on how to implement web components inside Angular
- Testing components as framework agnostic and in Angular
- Writing unit and end-to-end tests
- Actively conducting code reviews

Frontend Developer

Valcon Croatia [1 Apr 2022 - 1 Jan 2023]

Address: Ul. Domovinskog rata 61, 21000, Split, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: https://valcon.com/hr

Name of unit or department: Cloud Software Engineering - Business or sector: Professional, scientific and

technical activities

Pando Mission Control

Key management system, video game industry connector as well as easy and secure digital distribution. Video game keys tend to be distributed in an old fashioned way through excel sheets and similar which may lead to security breaches and can be really hard to maintain and track. Pando aims for automating key distribution, from developers to publishers and retailers, in a secure and innovative way as well as providing a game changer video game industry platform for keys, assets and pricing management.

In the team of 15+ people, my role is developing complex and intuitive UI as a frontend developer using technologies such as Angular framework in combination with the PrimeNg UI library. I strive towards making a reactive UI using RxjS library and NgRx state management as well as scalable architecture starting from component based approach, using ITCSS scalable and maintainable methodology. Application was managed through Azure cloud and Git version control system.

Tasks performed:

- Setting up initial project in Angular and implementing scalable and maintainable architecture
- Developed pixel perfect complex UI/UX
- Implementing state management
- Introducing best practices using component based approach
- Testing
- Participated in daily meetings as well as presenting development progress directly to client
- Brainstorming regurarly with the team to implement clean and efficient solutions
- Proposing ideas to make UI/UX intuinitive and simple with modern feel and look

Full Stack Web Developer

Infomedica d.o.o. [29 Sep 2019 – 14 Oct 2021]

Address: Šime Ljubića 55, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: https://infomedica.hr

Business or sector: Information and communication

Focused on building Radiological Information System (RIS) used to simplify medical workflow starting from patient admission all the way through generating medical report. I was committed to implement UI design as simple as possible with all functions just a few clicks away.



Desired outcome was to create centralized system which contains medical reports and radiological images in one place. Also, one of the goals behind the project is to reduce paper and plastic emission through digitalization. I've been part of the collaboration which included tech team and medical staff (doctors, nurses and medical radiology engineers) despite working from home during COVID-19 pandemic. Development workflow from design, to development and deployment to company test server took various knowledge and skills like learning medical workflows and institution hierarchies as well as disciplined approach to immerse myself into medical staff thinking.

The tools used for the software maintenance are Gitlab for development and TeamCity for CI/CD and IIS server for deployment.

Web application took a tablet-first friendly approach which was achieved using front end technologies like Angular, HTML, CSS and Javascript as well as UI libraries like Bootstrap, CoreUI and PrimeNG.

Data for the application was fetched from SQL relational database with the combination of back end frameworks like .NET Core, EF Core and REST APIs which were tested through Postman.

As the experience grew, I was entrusted with the responsibility to maintain DICOM CD/DVD Burner software with regional clients and Medical Scheduler software.

Tasks performed:

- Based on existing desktop application, redesigned and created RIS as a web solution
- Created and developed front-end and back-end projects from scratch
- Implemented simpler UI design and improved some of the existing features
- Implemented full administration CRUD operations containing organizations, hospitals, departments etc. including search and server-side pagination
- Imported 3rd party calendar module for appointment management
- Added internationalization for Croatian and English languages
- Developed authentication mechanism using JWT on both back-end and front-end
- Implemented light and dark theme
- Tested APIs through Postman
- Refactoring conducted regularly
- Application state management using Observables
- · Participated in database structuring
- Deployed to IIS

Software Development Lecturer

Jantar - Foreign Language School [Aug 2018 - Jun 2019]

Address: Poljička cesta 26A, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: https://www.jantar.hr/hr Business or sector: Education

Course goal was to introduce youth with the general programming ideas and to present the basics of C++ programming language.

Program of the course included programming principles such as variables, conditional statements, loops, arrays and functions and also how to use Visual Studio to create new projects and run console applications.

Main task was to keep the curriculum simple, effective and entertaining through presenting and demonstrating programming ideas linking them with real life examples.

According to the curriculum progress, I had to quickly adapt to the students capabilities which benefits my presentation skills and performances.

Tasks performed:

- Keeping track of student attendance using Amber School Management Software
- Used presentation and practical approach
- Introduced students with general programming principles using real life examples
- Encouraged problem-solving thinking when approaching task requirements
- Explained basics of C++ programming language variables, if statements, loops, arrays and functions
- Showed how to run a console application
- Conducted quick verbal examinations
- Combined acquired knowledge and applied it to the applications complexity as the curriculum progressed



Freelancer Self invested projects

Just a few personal, currently not in production, worthwhile mentioning self invested projects:

Oglasomat - hybrid mobile appliaction within master thesis practical part that simplifies, speeds up and notifies user with new listings found on local advertising website according to personal preferences. Built with Ionic UI library on top of Angular with the use of SQLite relational database and TypeORM Object-Relational Mapping tool.

Tasks performed:

- Designed simple UI containing Agents and Listings tabs using Ionic UI library on top of Angular framework
- Using TypeORM and SQLite, added Agent and Listing entities and associated repositories/services
- Apache Cordova used as a native wrapper to access device native APIs and to generate Android/iOS applications
- · Agents and Listings are stored to a user's mobile device
- Added scrapping mechanism
- Implemented CRUD for Agents with possibility to delete them all at once
- Added form validation when creating agent as well as auto populating Agent URL when exiting in-app browser used to filter listings by personal preferences
- Listings can also be deleted all at once as well as individual agent listings
- · Actions like delete all and mark as read are handled through modals and toast messages
- Entering individual Agent updates its listings
- Agents and Listings tabs have search functionality
- To simplify updating listings, added "pull down to refresh" feature
- Developed local notifications system when new listings are found in the background
- Implemented number of unread listings badge both on listings and individual agents

GigBook - partnership with colleague, in development using Angular as front end stack as well as .NET Core, EF Core and SQL relational database regarding back end technologies. Starting idea was to have mini social website that would help local event organisers to avoid event overlapping which would consequently enhance visitors number in venues. Further brainstorming has led us to incorporation of freelancers and organisers in the terms of audio-visual freelance jobs.

Tasks performed:

- Created back-end project with initial database connection setup
- Implemented login/logout mechanism using JWT
- Created CRUD REST APIs
- Worked on homepage and user profile UI
- Created user profile with basic user and organization information highlighting primary user organization which can be edited
- Implemented feature where user can have multiple organizations
- Changing user password feature isolated from editing user profile
- Application supports CRUD for user events including basic filtering
- Manually created and wrote SQL scripts
- Conducted every-day meetings and code reviews on every merge request
- Actively participated in structuring and handling database

MusicPlayer - team leader in college project built using Android Studio and Java. Simple music player that reads music from smartphone storage. Files can be played through title, album or artist section and has online lyrics feature implemented.

Network Infrastructure Maintenance Assistant

Hrvatski Telekom d.d. [Nov 2017 – Aug 2018]

Address: Vinkovačka 19, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: https://www.t.ht.hr



Name of unit or department: Network Infrastructure Management Department (T4.3) - Business or sector: Information and communication

Although the position wasn't software development oriented, primary focus was solving network infrastructure problems to identify correct positions of the telephone and/or internet network pipes and cables.

Data collected using network infrastructure knowledge and deduction skills had to be explicitly presented and inserted into specialized network infrastructure software which is then the foundation for the specialized field tech crew.

Main challenge was to correctly and precisely interpret and determine network element position using AutoCAD drawing template as a reference.

Key achievements are problem solving, deduction skills improvement and teamwork.

Tasks performed:

- Indicating network pipes/cables location based on AutoCAD drawing templates and Google Maps
- Inserting collected data to DDS specialized infrastructure software
- Maintaining old templates in physical form as well as digitalizing data

Stage technician & Live Sound Engineer (Volunteer)

Koalicija Udruga Mladih - KUM (Coalition of Youth Associations) [Dec 2013 - Dec 2020]

Address: Ulica Slobode 28, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: https://www.kum-split.hr

Business or sector: Arts, entertainment and recreation

Entire volunteer experience was dedicated to improve and strenghten audio-technical skills, music culture and to recruite new volunteers in the terms of the stage and audio requirements which consequently improved teaching and mentoring skills.

Key challenges were adapting to various artist stage plots, solving technical and audio issues, collaborating with other organization departments as well as the audio equipment maintenance.

Gained knowledge and skills are teamwork with various event organization departments and artists which led to social skills upgrade, coordination and management of stage operations and equipment, audio equipment maintenance, solving technical problems, live sound mixing.

Despite the volunteer status, current experience qualifies me for the proffesional gigs and events as the live sound engineer.

Tasks performed:

- Solving technical and audio complex issues during events
- Maintaining and coordinating stage equipment
- · Live sound (concert) mixing
- · Collaborating with various organization departments and artists, domestic and foreign
- Participated in multiple audio workshops
- Educated and mentored new volunteers

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master of Science - MS

FESB - Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Naval Architecture [Aug 2017 – Sep 2019]

Address: Ulica Ruđera Boškovića 32, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: http://www.fesb.unist.hr

Field(s) of study: Communication and Information Technology

Final grade: A - Excellent

Thesis: Mobile application development using Web technologies



Bachelor of Science - BS

FESB - Faculty of Electrical Engineering, Mechanical Engineering and Naval Architecture [Aug 2013 – Jul 2017]

Address: Ulica Ruđera Boškovića 32, 21000 Split (Croatia)

Website: http://www.fesb.unist.hr

Field(s) of study: Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

Final grade: A - Excellent

Thesis: Discrete cosinus transformation application in audio signal compression

Economist

Economic and Bureau High School [Aug 2009 – Jun 2013]

Address: Vukovarska 37, 21000 Split (Croatia)
Website: http://ss-ekonomskaiupravna-st.skole.hr/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Croatian

Other language(s):

English

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B1

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user